霍达尔 6-2 6-3 布勃利克 · 赛后场上采访
Rafa, congratulations.
拉法 恭喜你
What a debut.
好一场首秀
You must be incredibly happy
你一定非常开心
and proud of that performance.
也为这场表现骄傲吧
Yeah, thank you. Thank you very much.
是的 谢谢 非常感谢
It was a pleasure, you know,
很荣幸
to represent Team Europe for the first time.
第一次代表欧洲队出战
I think I felt great on court.
我觉得在场上感觉很好
I played against a very tough player.
对手是一个非常难缠的球员
So, I think the atmosphere here is great.
我觉得这里的气氛太棒了
So, thank you very much to all the people
非常感谢所有
that came.
来看球的人
It's been such a 12 months for you
这12个月对你来说
to watch the improvement
看着你一路进步
and how dramatically you've risen up
排名蹿升
the rankings.
有多快
Every time you come to an event,
你每去一个比赛
it's a first time.
都是第一次
Explain what it's been like
说说第一次来拉沃尔杯
to come to the Laver Cup,
是什么感觉
a team event for the first time.
第一次打团体赛
Yeah, it's totally different.
是的 完全不一样
You know, I come from different conditions
我来的地方条件完全不同
to play from Davis Cup in clay, you know,
刚打完戴维斯杯的红土
far away.
在很远的地方
So yeah, I got the call, you know,
然后我接到电话
from Yannick that if I wanted
诺阿问我愿不愿意
to represent team Europe and yeah,
代表欧洲队 我当时
I didn't think the two times.
想都没想
I think it's great to be in an event
能来参加这样的比赛
where I can compete, you know,
和世界上最好的球员
and be in the same team
在同一支队伍里
with the best players in the world.
我觉得太好了
So it's a pleasure for me
所以对我来说很荣幸
and I'm very grateful.
我非常感激
But tell us
不过给我们讲讲
about how you think 12 months ago,
12个月前你怎么想
did you ever dream of that moment?
你梦到过这一刻吗？
I mean, I imagine you wanted to be here.
我猜你是想来这里的
Did you think it would happen that quickly?
你想过会来得这么快吗？
Well, I mean to be honest,
说实话
no, I think it has come very fast to me.
没有 我觉得一切来得太快了
Many things, you know, in this year.
今年很多事情都是
So, I think it's now at the end
所以我觉得现在赛季快结束
of the season time to process
是时候好好消化
and analyze all the things
分析一下这些事
because everything has come very fast
因为一切都来
to me.
太快了
But at the same time, I'm very happy,
但同时我也很开心
you know, how the things are going
事情的发展
and I'm eager, you know, to keep improving
我也很渴望继续进步
and be a better player next year.
明年成为更好的球员
That's a problem for the rest of the tour.
巡回赛其他人可要头疼了
I've got to tell you.
我得告诉你
One thing though, you started
不过有件事 你曾经
a very brief time in college.
在大学打过很短一段时间
you decided to turn pro.
然后你决定转职业
It's been the right decision.
事实证明这个决定是对的
But that period
但那段
of being in college tennis,
打大学网球的日子
which is very competitive,
竞争很激烈
is it a lot like coming out
是不是很像
and playing in this environment?
在这种环境下打球？
Yeah, it's a team event, you know,
是的 这是团体赛
so there are many similarities.
所以有很多相似之处
So, yeah, I think
所以 没错
that year at the in college really helped me,
大学那一年真的帮了我
you know, to be in this kind
让我能打这种比赛
of events playing with a team
和团队一起打
and for other players, you know,
为其他球员而打
it's not just for you.
不只是为你自己
So, yeah,
所以
it's great to play in a team event,
能打团体赛太好了
in a team event for the first time.
第一次打团体赛
So, I'm, you know,
所以我
very very happy about that.
非常非常开心
Well, I know your team are very happy
我知道你的队友也很开心
about it.
为你高兴
We'll let you get inside
我们让你回去吧
and the way you play today,
看你今天这么打
I think there's going
我觉得会有
to be plenty more Laver Cup towels
更多拉沃尔杯毛巾
that you can put into your bag as well.
装进你的包里
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
是的 是的
I'm very happy, you know, to represent.
我很高兴能代表欧洲队
So, yeah. I also want to thank Roger
我还想感谢费德勒
who was in the stands, you know,
他在看台上
watching me.
看我打球
So, yeah. Thank you much.
谢谢
And also, yeah, it's a pleasure that he's
而且很荣幸他
in the stands and the work he's doing,
在看台上 还有他
you know, in this tournament.
为这项比赛做的一切
and also Rod, that is named
还有罗德
after the tournament, after him.
这项比赛就是以他命名的
It's a pleasure to see him, you know,
很荣幸能看到他
in the stands watching this type of matches.
在看台上看这样的比赛
So, thank you very much, guys,
所以非常感谢你们
for being there.
到场
Well done, Rafa.
打得好 拉法
Once again, congratulations.
再次恭喜